Guide to the Charles H. Hapgood Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Charles H. Hapgood papers
1898-1979
1950-1979
YCAL MSS 283
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
16.27
(39 boxes)
The Charles H. Hapgood Papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts, and research materials related to Hapgood's research projects and publications on earth science, archeology, ancient history, parapsychology, and spirit communication.
Hapgood, Charles H.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles H. Hapgood, 1982
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 39 contains restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Associated Materials
Additional Charles H. Hapgood material can be found in the Hapgood Family Papers (YCAL MSS 41) and the Miriam Hapgood DeWitt Papers (YCAL MSS 277) at the Beinecke Library, and the Hapgood Family Papers (manuscript group 795) in Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library. Additional material related to Hapgood's work with the medium Elwood Babbitt, as well as the manuscripts of his books on psychic studies, are in the Charles Hapgood Papers (MS 445) at the W. E. B. Du Bois Library, University of Massachusetts.
Charles Hutchins Hapgood (1904-1982)
Charles Hutchins Hapgood was the son of the journalists and authors Hutchins Hapgood (1869-1944) and Neith Boyce (1872-1951). He was born in New York City on May 17, 1904, and, along with his siblings Harry Boyce (1901-1918), Miriam (1906-1990), and Beatrix (1910-1994), was raised in the family's homes in New York and Provincetown, Massachusetts. Hapgood attended the Scarborough School in Westchester County, New York, and then, like his father, earned two degrees at Harvard University: an A.B. (1929) and M.A. (1932). Staying on in Cambridge, he completed the course requirements for a history Ph.D. but not his dissertation. After holding an administrative job at the Provincetown Community Center, and wartime positions with the Office of Strategic Services and the American Red Cross in Washington, D.C., Hapgood began a twenty-year teaching career in the humanities through faculty appointments at Keystone College (1945-1947), Springfield College (1947-1952), Keene State College (1956-1966), and New England College (1966-1967), where he lectured in world and American history, anthropology, economics, and the history of science.
Throughout his academic career, as well as in his retirement years, Hapgood pursued personal research projects that centered on controversial, and largely disputed, topics. His first published work was The Earth's Shifting Crust: a Key to Some Basic Problems of Earth Sciences (1958), which was revised and reissued in 1970 as The Path of the Pole. In these books he explored his theories about the movements of the outer layer of the earth and the resulting polar shifts, which he believed to have influenced the formation of various mountain ranges and the changing size and level of the oceans and seas. Hapgood's follow-up work, Maps of the Ancient Sea Kings: Evidence of Advanced Civilization in the Ice Age (1966, revised edition 1979), suggested that Antarctica had been a habitable continent prior to the shift of the earth's outer layer. His research was based in large part on a portolan chart drawn in 1513 by Piri Reis, a Turkish admiral and cartographer, which had been discovered in 1929 in an Istanbul library. Hapgood had earlier given a presentation on the map at the Tenth International Congress of the History of Science (Ithaca, New York, 1962). His continuing interest in ancient civilizations led to his publication Mystery in Acámbaro: an account of the ceramic collection of the late Waldemar Julsrud in Acámbaro, Gto., Mexico (1973), which discussed the more than 30,000 clay figures that had been excavated there in the summer of 1944; Hapgood supported Julsrud's belief that the figures (representing humans from a variety of civilizations, as well as dinosaurs), which were found in near-perfect condition, had been created and buried several thousand years before. However, most academics believed them to be a hoax, and made for Julsrud by twentieth-century Mexican peasants. In addition to these works, Hapgood reached the general public through articles he wrote for the Saturday Evening Post and Coronet magazines, and with his book for children, Great Mysteries of the Earth, which was published in 1960; it was also issued in Arabic.
Concurrent with his investigations in the fields of earth science, ancient history, and archeology, Hapgood was actively interested in parapsychology and spirit communication. He spent a decade working with the New England medium Elwood Babbitt (1921-2001) to encounter nearly sixty notables in divinity and history, both recent and ancient. The conversations were taped and transcribed, and provided Hapgood with material for his final three books: Voices of Spirit, Through the Psychic Experience of Elwood Babbitt (1975), Talks with Christ and His Teachers Through the Psychic Gift of Elwood Babbitt (1981), and The God Within: a Testament of Vishnu, a Handbook for the Spiritual Renaissance (1982).
Charles Hapgood's 1941 marriage to Tamsin Hughes (1906-1998) ended in divorce in 1955. In his later years he resided in Arizona and in Richmond, New Hampshire, but was living in Greenfield, Massachusetts, when he was struck by a car and died on December 21, 1982. Charles and Tamsin Hapgood were survived by two sons, Frederick (born 1942) and William (born 1944), and two grandsons.
Scope and Contents
The Charles H. Hapgood Papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts, and research materials related to Hapgood's research projects and publications on earth science, archeology, ancient history, parapsychology, and spirit communication. The bulk of the material is letters from and to a wide array of people interested in Hapgood's work and theories, or, in some cases, those in whom he hoped to create an interest. His correspondents ranged from amateur geologists and local historians to respected scholars from around the world, as Hapgood's interests were equally wide-ranging: ancient maps to New Age philosophies, terrestrial science to celestial spirits. The collection holds little in the way of Hapgood family papers, although solid insight on Charles Hapgood's personality and personal life can be gleaned from many of his outgoing letters.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series: I. Personal Papers (1913-1979); II. Writings (1918-1979); and Other Papers (1898-1979).
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Cartography -- History; Early maps; Earth (Planet) -- Crust; Glacial epoch; Prehistoric peoples; Psychic ability; Psychic readings; Spirit writings; Acámbaro (Guanajuato, Mexico) -- Description and travel; Sound recordings; Amos, (Biblical prophet: Spirit); Elizabeth, (Spirit), I, 1533-1603; Jesus Christ, (Spirit); John, the Baptist, Saint (Spirit); Nostradamus, (Spirit), 1503-1566; Pirî Reis, -1554?; Socrates, (Spirit); Babbitt, Elwood, 1922-; Delair, J. B., 1932-; DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1906-1990; Einstein, Albert, (Spirit), 1879-1955; Faust, Beatrix Hapgood, 1910-; Frankland, John Middleton; Gandhi, (Spirit), 1869-1948; Gardner, Erle Stanley, 1889-1970; Gordon, Cyrus H. (Cyrus Herzl), 1908-2001; Hapgood, Charles H.; Hapgood, Fred; Hapgood, Hutchins, 1869-1944; Homet, Marcel, 1897-1982; Johnson, Lyndon B., (Spirit) (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973; Julsrud, Waldemar; Kennedy, John F., (Spirit) (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963; Lincoln, Abraham, (Spirit), 1809-1865; Lodge, Oliver, (Spirit), 1851-1940; Mallery, Arlington Humphrey; Mather, Kirtley F. (Kirtley Fletcher), 1888-1978; Millikan, Robert Andrews, (Spirit), 1868-1953; Mills, James Porter, (Spirit); Pike, James A., (Spirit) (James Albert), 1913-1969; Pilate, Pontius, (Spirit), active 1st century; Rainey, Froelich G. (Froelich Gladstone), 1907-1992; Regler, Margaret; Rennell of Rodd, Francis James Rennell Rodd, Baron, 1895-1978; Sanderson, Ivan Terence, 1911-1973; Twain, Mark, (Spirit), 1835-1910; Wordsworth, William, (Spirit), 1770-1850; Society for the Investigation of the Unexplained; Gabriel, (Archangel); Krishna, (Hindu deity)
- Personal Papers, 1913-1979; Series I; 2.92; (8 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries: Family Correspondence and Papers; Hutchins Hapgood and Neith Boyce Estates; and General Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains material that is both personal and professional in nature, primarily letters written between Hapgood and his sisters, aunt, and other family members, and between Hapgood and his friends and colleagues. The Family Correspondence and Papers also contains Hapgood's international certificate of vaccination, and a group of newspaper articles about him and his work. The subseries Hutchins Hapgood and Neith Boyce Estates contains letters between Charles Hapgood and researchers working with his parents' papers, and typed transcripts of some of his father's essays. More extensive correspondence with the same people and others related to the management of the Hapgood and Boyce literary estates can be found in the Miriam Hapgood DeWitt Papers (YCAL MSS 277).
  While the bulk of the letters relating to Charles Hapgood's research and publications are held in Series II Writings, the subseries of General Correspondence here contains files for people with whom Hapgood had professional relationships that spanned both many years and his various research projects, such as Robert Merritt, Ivan Sanderson, and his agent, Oliver Swan, as well as publishers Alfred A. Knopf and the Chilton Book Company. Also here are letters from former students, and long-time friends such as his high school classmate Jack Frankland. Intimate details of Hapgood's personal and financial affairs can be found in the correspondence with his lawyer, Arthur A. Atha. Copies of obituaries written for Hapgood are in the papers of his sister Miriam Hapgood DeWitt (YCAL MSS 277).
  - Family Correspondence and Papers
    - Bright, Edward, 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Faust, Alfred Luke, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Faust, Beatrix Hapgood, 1978 Mar-Apr (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hapgood, Charles H., 1961-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hapgood, David, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hapgood, Elizabeth, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hapgood, Elizabeth R., 1968-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hapgood, Fred
      - Correspondence, 1963-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 9-12)
      - Essay on Hutchins Hapgood, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Essays and articles, miscellaneous, 1968-1978
      - Space Shots book, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Hapgood, Norman and Ruth, 1962, 1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Hapgood, Scott, 1974-1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Hapgood, Will, 1964-1979 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - Souza, Neith Faust, 1978 Mar-Apr (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Hutchins Hapgood and Neith Boyce Estates
    - Correspondence
      - Cronin, Paula, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Dennis, Marta, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - France, Rachel, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Green-Wood Cemetery, 1961 Jun 15 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Marcaccio, Michael, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Marriner, Gerald, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
      - Roloff, Carol, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - University Microfilms International, 1964-1977 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - University of Washington Press, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Other Papers
      - Hapgood's essays, 1913, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
        Transcriptions of Hapgood's writings in the New York Globe and Commercial Advertiser (1913), and reprint from Camera Work (1913)
      - The Story of a Lover (bound reprint from microfilm), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - General Correspondence
    - Abrons, Stanley H., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Adventurers Club, 1972 Mar 5 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Aldridge, Adelaide, 1969 Oct 10 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Ashworth, Fred L., 1974-1974 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Atha, Arthur A., 1955-1970 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Bailey, Herbert, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
    - Bartholomew, Alick, 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Berlitz, Charles, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Borwell, Skip, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Brinton, Crane, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Brosseau, Mark, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Campbell, James
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: McLauren, Laura
    - Casey, Barry, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Cheney, David M., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Chilton Book Company, 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 47-53)
      See also: Letters
    - Chilton Book Company, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 54-56)
    - Colby, Al, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Collier, John, 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Cook, Charles, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Covey, Joan, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Dix, Byron E. and Katherine, 1975-1978, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Einaudi, Giulio, 1970 Oct 14 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Faney, James J. and Adele, 1978 Nov 2 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Frankland, Jack, 1963-1979 (Box 4, Folder 64-68)
      See also: DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood
    - Gale, Irving H., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Gauger, Edgar, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Goddard College, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Grand, Mary, 1974 Apr 26 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      More extensive correspondence between Hapgood and Grand is in the Miriam Hapgood DeWitt Papers (YCAL MSS 277).
    - Green, Clare, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Greenwald, Harold, 1967 May 29 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Hammett, Fred S., 1941-1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Harvard University, 1951, 1953, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Healion, James, 1962 Aug 27 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Henderson, David D., 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - The Illustrated London News, 1959 Dec 18 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - International Correspondence Center, 1965 May 8 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Isis, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Isroe, Alfred, 1964-1974 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Jessup, Mary, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Kemp, Robert, 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 84-85)
    - Kiefer, Gerry, 1979 Jul 8 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Kotowski, Karen, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Kraske, Robert, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Larson, Kenneth Lloyd, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Lee, Paul H., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Lloyd, Eaton, 1973 Jan 8 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - McConnell, John, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - McGowan, Harold, 1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - McIntyre, Thomas J., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - McLauren, Laura, 1961-1970 (Box 5, Folder 95-97)
    - McMurrin, Sterling, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Mahoney, Ted, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Mailer, Norman, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Malsbenden, John F., 1963 Sep 9 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Malthaner, Hubert, 1962-1975 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Manhattan Gazette, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Mather, Kirtley F., 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Mathey, Barbara, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Matusow, Job, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Merritt, Robert L., 1962-1974 (Box 6, Folder 107-110)
    - Moore, Eleanor A., 1979 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - New York Tribune, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Ohio Historical Society, 1962 Oct 1 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Onder, Kerim, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - O'Neil, Gene, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Pearce, Charles A., 1951-1954 (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Pensée, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Perry, Bernard, 1955-1960 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Phillips Publishing Company, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Place, Nancy, 1978 Jul 7 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Pompano, Debbie, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Publishers - miscellaneous, 1972-1977 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Raphaelion, Harry M., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Redfearn, D. H., 1959-1967 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Richards, Bennett W., 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - Roberts, Leo, 1961-1977 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - Robertson, Carl V., 1978 Sep 13 (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Rothovius, Andrew, 1963-1973 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Rubin, Louis D., 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Sanderson, Ivan T.
      - Letters, 1956-1972 (Box 7, Folder 130-141)
      - Articles, 1952, 1969, undated (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - Schuerger, Alan, undated (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - Scott, John Anthony, 1966-1971 (Box 8, Folder 144)
    - Shapley, Harlow and Willis, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - Spraggett, Allen, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - Strachan, Richard W., 1973 (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Stuhlmann, Gunther, 1967-1973 (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Swan, Oliver, 1954-1971 (Box 8, Folder 149-151)
    - Tomas, Andrew, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 152)
    - Turnstone Books
      See: Bartholomew, Alick
    - Turolla, Pino, 1975 May 30 (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - Union Internationale de la Press Scientifique, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 154)
    - Viva International, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 155)
    - Wasserman, Harvey, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 156)
    - West Chester State College, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 157)
    - White, Mary F., undated (Box 8, Folder 158)
    - Willis, Paul J., 1977 Apr 14 (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - Wright, John K., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 160)
    - Zacharko, Bohdan, undated (Box 8, Folder 161)
- Writings, 1918-1979; Series II; 9.39; (26 boxes)
  Organized into five subseries: Archeology; Children's Books; Earth's Shifting Crust; Maps of the Ancient Sea Kings; and Psychic Studies.
  The series contains correspondence and subject files supporting Hapgood's research projects and writings, as well as manuscripts, drafts, and galley sheets related to the production of his books; files related to the latter appear at the start of each subseries, followed by correspondence and subject files, if there are any. The subject files hold academic and research material such as journal offprints, drawings, slides, and photographs sent to Hapgood, some at his request and others to substantiate the writer's points. Hapgood also had transcribed entire chapters of books, and put the copies (some in carbon, others in mimeograph) in the correspondence files under the author's name. In one case, a typed copy of a short Turkish book on the Piri Reis map was made so that it could be distributed to his students via the then-popular medium of mimeograph. Because Hapgood's topics and consultants were somewhat overlapping in time and scope, material related to one subseries may also appear in the other subseries. In addition, some correspondence related to his research is filed in the General Correspondence subseries of Series I, so readers are encouraged to look there as well, if attempting to locate all information on a particular project.
  Material in the subseries Archeology pertains primarily to Hapgood's work on the clay figures discovered in Acámbaro, Mexico. Of note here is a decade's worth of letters from Erle Stanley Gardner (1889-1970), a respected author of detective fiction, who was interested enough in the mystery of the figurines to provide financial support for Hapgood's investigation. The Children's Books subseries has files on Hapgood's published work Great Mysteries of the Earth, as well as proposals and drafts of his unpublished story "The Little Rhinoceros."
  The subseries Earth's Shifting Crust contains files related to that 1958 title as well as its revised edition, The Path of the Pole (1971), in which Hapgood made use of up-to-date technological advancements to support his theories of continental drift and climate change. The subseries Maps of the Ancient Sea Kings includes material related to Hapgood's book, and shorter writings on the Piri Reis map and other portolan charts, as well as information about unusual aerial phenomena (UFOs).
  Material in the subseries Psychic Studies is arranged under three headings: Correspondence; Spirit Communications; and Subject Files. This subseries contains transcripts, voiceprints, and one tape recording of sessions held with the medium Elwood Babbitt, as well as a file on hospital tests that Hapgood had conducted on Babbitt. It also includes a number of research papers written by Hapgood's college students, describing experiments on the effect of musical and mental projections on the growth of plants and the actions of household pets.
  - Archeology
    - Book production, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 162-163)
    - Correspondence
      - Adams, Sherman, 1958-1960 (Box 9, Folder 164-165)
      - American Cosmic/Solar Research Center, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 166)
      - Ashworth, Fred L., 1960-1968 (Box 9, Folder 167)
      - Bloom, Murray Teigh, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 168)
      - Caine, Ralph L., 1959 (Box 9, Folder 169)
      - Cabrera, Javier, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 170)
      - Collier, Donald, 1955-1958 (Box 9, Folder 171)
      - Cox, Alice, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 172)
      - Daniken, Erich von, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 173)
      - Delair, Justin B., 1959-1970 (Box 9, Folder 174-175)
      - Elberfeld, Stephen, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 176)
      - Fate magazine, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 177)
      - Fuller, Mary Margaret
        See: Fate magazine
      - Gardner, Erle Stanley
        - Correspondence, 1956-1969 (Box 9, Folder 178-179)
        - Desert Magazine article, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 180)
      - Gardner, Jean Bethell, 1971-1978 (Box 9, Folder 181)
      - Geiger, Margaret, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 182)
      - Glynn, Frank, 1959 Jun 11 (Box 10, Folder 183)
      - Harries, Eloise Street, 1958-1963 (Box 10, Folder 184)
      - Hehr, Frederick G., 1960 Mar 31 (Box 10, Folder 185)
      - Home, W. Scott, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 186)
      - Homet, Marcel F., 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 187)
      - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 188)
      - Julsrud, Carlos, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 189)
      - Keeler, Clyde, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 190)
      - Kennedy, George, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 191)
      - Koson, Peter D., 1965 (Box 10, Folder 192)
      - Krieger, Alex D., 1952-1956 (Box 10, Folder 193)
      - Lee, Ivan, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 194-202)
      - Luke, Terry, 1969-1971 (Box 10, Folder 203)
      - Malouf, Lucian
        See: Mechanicsburg (Pennsylvania) expedition
      - Mertz, Henriette, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 204)
      - Paddock, John, 1956-1963 (Box 10, Folder 205)
      - Price, Derek J., 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 206)
      - Prideaux, Thomas, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 207)
      - Rainey, Froelich G., 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 208)
      - Regler, Margaret (Peggy), 1966-1978 (Box 11, Folder 209)
        See also: Correspondence
      - Rice, Theresa, 1968-1975 (Box 11, Folder 210)
      - Rowe, Stanley, 1957-1961 (Box 11, Folder 211)
      - Sargent, Howard R., 1962 (Box 11, Folder 212)
      - Shoenborn, Wolfgang, Mrs., 1972 Jan 18 (Box 11, Folder 213)
      - Smith, Bradley, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 214)
      - Stern, Joseph, 1975 Jan 27 (Box 11, Folder 215)
      - Sykes, Egerton, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 216)
      - Tierney, John, 1961-1974 (Box 11, Folder 217)
      - Vallette, W. L., 1953-1966 (Box 11, Folder 218)
      - Wagner, George, 1973 Nov 24 (Box 11, Folder 219)
      - Wang, Arthur M., 1963 (Box 11, Folder 220)
      - Ware, Winthrop, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 221)
      - Williams, John G., 1958-1967 (Box 11, Folder 222-224)
      - Willis, Ronald J., 1966-1970 (Box 11, Folder 225)
      - Young, Arthur M., 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 226)
      - Zink, David, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 227)
    - Subject file
      - Mechanicsburg (Pennsylvania) expedition, 1959, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 228)
  - Children's books
    - Great Mysteries of the Earth
      - Correspondence
        - G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1959-1969 (Box 12, Folder 229)
        - Sturz, Herbert, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 230)